wevideo.com 2019-12-09

# WeVideo | Privacy Policy

_Last Modified: June 7, 2019_

For WeVideo Education Services Privacy Policy, please click here

Data privacy is important to WeVideo. We believe you should always know how information about you is collected, used, and disclosed by WeVideo when you use our services, or otherwise interact with us.

We respect the privacy rights of our users and recognize the importance of protecting information collected about you. If you use WeVideo as part of an entity or organization that has an agreement with WeVideo (like your employer or an educational institution), the terms of that organization’s contract for the WeVideo service may restrict our collection or use of your information more than what is described in this Privacy Policy notice.

WeVideo provides tools to control your personal data, including the ability to consent or withdraw consent for its collection and use.

This Privacy Policy applies to WeVideo sites, apps, communications, and services (“Services”).

This Privacy Policy applies to your use of our Services. We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time, and will post the most current version on our website. If a revision meaningfully reduces your rights, we will notify you.

WeVideo's data protection officer is Krishna Menon, reachable at data.protection.officer@wevideo.com

Contact information for WeVideo:

  * WeVideo, Inc.
  * 1975 W El Camino Real
  * Suite 202
  * Mountain View, CA 94040
  * Tel: (650) 800-3400

## Things you create or provide to us

When you create a WeVideo Account, you provide us with personal information that includes your name and, when not using single sign-on, an email address and a password. For example, if you use Google single sign-on, you authorize WeVideo to create an account that is identified with your Google credentials and, in this case, you do not need to create a new password since you will authenticate yourself using your Google credentials. 

Even if you aren’t signed in to a WeVideo Account, you might choose to provide us with information — like an email address to receive updates about our services.

When you upload content such as videos, photos, and audio for use within the services, we collect that content within your account so that you may access it.

We also collect comments you make on videos, be they your own or those that others have shared with you.

We use payment processors such as Stripe and PayPal to process your online payments. The payment data required to process the financial transaction resides on the servers of the payment processors, and is not on our servers.

## Information we collect as you use our services

#### Your browsers and devices

We collect information about browsers and devices you use to access WeVideo services, which helps us troubleshoot and make improvements to our services.

The information we collect includes the following:

  * your device’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address
  * type of mobile device you use
  * operating system of your device
  * browser type
  * non-precise geographic location (e.g. country, city, zip code)
  * technical information about your device, system and App software, and peripherals
  * date and time stamps associated with transactions
  * system configuration information

We collect this information when a service on your device contacts our servers — for example, when you install a WeVideo app on your mobile device or when you connect to our services through your browser.

#### Your privacy and cookies

When you visit a website, it may store or retrieve information on your browser, mostly in the form of cookies. This information might be about you, your preferences or your device and is mostly used to make the site work as you expect it to. The information does not usually directly identify you, but it can give you a more personalized web experience. Some types of cookies are required for WeVideo to provide a functional site or services, other types of cookies are designed to enhance our site or services. You can choose to accept or refuse the cookies that are not strictly necessary. You may review details of our Cookie Policy to understand the benefits of accepting optional cookies.

#### Your activity

We collect information about your activity when using our services. We process this information to provide you with service, to maintain a reliable quality of service, and to provide you with improved services.

Activity that we collect may include:

  * Purchase activity
  * Terms you search for
  * Features that you use
  * Published videos you watch
  * People with whom you communicate or share content when using services
  * Information that you provide to us to connect external services of your choosing with our services 
  * What third party sites you publish to (such as Google Drive, Facebook, Twitter)
  * Responses to surveys

We do not sell any information that we collect about you or your activity.

We do not share personally identifiable activity information with trusted third parties unless you provide your consent or provide such information when interacting with a third party form. 

When we track anonymously, we use methods so that any tracking is not identified with you and is aggregated and processed in an anonymous manner.

#### Your location information

We collect information about your location when you use our services, which helps us offer features that may be localized by knowing the originating country of an IP address. This location information also helps us prevent harm and fraud, comply with law, serve the public interest, and keep WeVideo safe and welcoming for everyone.

We use various technologies to collect and store information, including cookies, pixel tags, local storage, such as browser web storage or application data caches, databases, and server logs.

## We use data to build better services

#### Communicate with you

We use information we collect, like your email address, to interact with you directly. For example, we may send you notifications about product updates, including new features, video tutorials, newsletters, special offers, and periodic tips to help you get the most out of the services. And if you contact WeVideo, we’ll keep a record of your request in order to help solve any issues you might be facing.

#### Provide, maintain, and improve our services

We use your information to deliver our services, like processing the terms you search for in order to return content that you can use in your creations, or by suggesting related content to help you improve your creative process.

We also use your information to ensure our services are working as intended, such as tracking outages or troubleshooting issues that you report to us. And we use your information to make improvements to our services — for example, understanding which features are most commonly used so that we can improve the manner in which you are able to access and use those features for a better user experience.

When you have issues or problems using our services, and you ask us to help troubleshoot those issues you report, we will analyze crash reports and usage characteristics of your account to help provide you with the best support.

#### Develop new services

We use the information we collect in our existing services to help us define and develop new services.

#### Personalize the user experience

We use the information we collect in our existing services to personalize and customize the user experience for you. For example, if we collect the type of content that you search for in our library of content, and you mark content as Favorite, we might return search results that are similar to content that you have previously marked as Favorite.

#### Measure performance

We use data for analytics and measurement to understand how our services are used. For example, we analyze data about the features that you use to optimize product design. We use a variety of tools to do this, including Google Analytics.

#### Third party partners

When you visit our website, if you consent, we will collect information about your interests on our website and share limited, non-personally identifiable data with trusted partners such as Facebook. This sharing will help us personalize any WeVideo ads we may present on other services (for example, Facebook). You manage your consent through the cookie bar on our website, as explained in our Cookie Policy.

* * *

## Your privacy controls

You have the final say about managing your privacy across our services. At any time, you can login to your account and use the controls provided in "Account settings" to limit the information we collect about you or how we use it. You can also choose to deactivate your WeVideo account. If you have any questions, please feel free to contact us.

#### Managing your personal information

You control the personal data you share with us. You can access or rectify this data at any time. You can also deactivate your account. We provide you with tools to restrict or withdraw consent where applicable for the use of data that you have provided to WeVideo. At your request we make the data you shared through our services portable and provide easy ways for you to contact us.

#### Accessing or rectifying your personal data

If you have registered an account on WeVideo, we provide you with tools and account settings to access, correct, delete, or modify the personal data you provided to us and that is associated with your account.

You can download certain account information, including videos and photos that you have uploaded and own, by following the instructions in "Account settings."

#### For how long do we store your data?

If you have initiated the process with us to sign up for service within the European Union, but have not completed the sign up process, we retain your personal data on our servers for up to 24 hours. In non-EU locations, in this situation, we will retain data for up to 60 days.

Once you complete the sign up process and we create an account to provide you with with service, we will store your data for as long as you are entitled to receive service from us.

If the service that you are receiving from us is free of charge (for example, a free plan or a trial) and the service has expired or you have been inactive on the service for four months, we will deem the free service to be abandoned by you, and will cancel the service and delete data you have uploaded or created (some examples are your uploaded content, finished videos, projects). Some personally identifiable data–for example, usage tracking–persists unless you request deletion by invoking your right to be forgotten.

#### Deletion

If you follow the instructions in "Account settings," your account will be deactivated and then deleted. When deactivated, your WeVideo account, including your display name, username, and public profile, will no longer be viewable on WeVideo.com, WeVideo for iOS, and WeVideo for Android.

When you delete any type of account to discontinue service, data is deleted after a short grace period following account deletion. If you choose to exercise your right to be forgotten when deleting your account or terminating service, your Data is immediately deleted.

#### Object, Restrict, or Withdraw Consent

 When you are logged into your WeVideo account, you can manage your privacy settings and other account features in "Account settings" at any time.

#### Portability

WeVideo provides you a means to download the information you have shared through our services by following the steps in "Account settings."

* * *

## Education services

WeVideo is committed to protecting the privacy of students. 

WeVideo has COPPA- and FERPA-compliant services ("School plans") that are offered to educational institutions such as schools. These educational services support many users belonging to the same School plan, with each user having their own login account.

When you belong to a School plan, your educational institution ("school") collects your personal data based on their own policies. For example, if you are a teacher or student in your school's plan, your school controls your data and WeVideo processes your data in accordance with privacy policies managed by your school.

#### Account owner data

When your school purchases a WeVideo School plan, a special account—the Account Owner—is created. Every School plan has an account owner. Account owner data that we collect is used to create, bill, and maintain the School plan service ("Owner data").

For example, if you sign up on our site as the Account owner for your School plan, your data is collected and processed in accordance with WeVideo's privacy policy.

#### Data for non-owners

Users in a School plan are subject to the privacy policy of their school. Some School plan users—those who are not students—may have the additional ability to control some privacy settings within the WeVideo service.

For example, if you are a teacher and you opt-out from all WeVideo privacy settings, then WeVideo is a processor of your Service data based on privacy policies established by your school. If on the other hand, you consent to some types of WeVideo data collection, then WeVideo's privacy policy will apply in those circumstances. For example, if you consent to receive WeVideo marketing communications to learn about our services and how to use them in your classroom, we will process that marketing data according to this privacy policy.

#### Students and student data privacy

If you are a student in a School plan, your student service data is processed in a way that is COPPA- and FERPA-compliant and you are always opted-out of WeVideo privacy settings. Your "Account settings" page will instruct you to contact your school for information about your school's privacy policy.

* * *

## Enterprise services

WeVideo has Enterprise services that are offered to businesses through direct sales channels. These Enterprise services support many users belonging to the same Enterprise instance, with each user having their own login account.

When you belong to an Enterprise service plan, the company that owns your plan ("company") collects your personal data based on their own policies. For example, your company controls your data and WeVideo processes your data in accordance with privacy policies managed by your company.

#### Account owner data

When your company purchases a WeVideo Enterprise service plan, a special account—the Account Owner—is created. Every Enterprise plan has an account owner. Account owner data that we collect is used to create, bill, and maintain the Enterprise plan service ("Owner data").

For example, if you sign up as the Account owner for your Enterprise plan, your data is collected and processed in accordance with WeVideo's privacy policy.

#### Data for non-owners

Users in an Enterprise plan are subject to the privacy policy of their company. Some Enterprise plans provide users with the additional ability to control some privacy settings within the WeVideo service.

For example, if you have privacy settings available in the "Account settings" section, and you opt-out from all WeVideo privacy settings, then WeVideo is a processor of your Service data based on privacy policies established by your company. If on the other hand, you consent to some types of WeVideo data collection, then WeVideo's privacy policy will apply in those circumstances. For example, if you consent to receive WeVideo marketing communications to learn about our services and how to use them in your work, we will process that marketing data according to this privacy policy.

* * *

## OUR POLICY TOWARD CHILDREN

WeVideo is committed to protecting the privacy of students and offers services that are fully compliant with the FERPA and COPPA rules and guidelines. In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) of 1998, the services are not intended for use if you are under 13 years of age unless one of the following is true: (1) you are using a WeVideo education plan ("WeVideo for Schools"). In that case, the policy above under the section EDUCATION SERVICES applies. For more details on COPPA, and how an application or website can be used in an educational context see [COPPA and Schools](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/complying-coppa-frequently-asked-questions#Schools). Or contact [education@wevideo.com](mailto:education@wevideo.com) (2) you have the consent of your parent or legal guardian or (3) when available use the application as a Guest User. As a Guest User, the application can be used without providing any personal data. Guest User mode is only available in some of the applications and is designed to allow usage of the application without providing any personal data. If you are not over 13 years of age and are not using the application as a Guest User, you will need to have the consent of your parent or guardian.

We may use any of the following methods to verify that you have your parents’ consent:

  * At registration, we will require that you provide your first name and a parent’s valid email address. We will send your parent a notification email stating that you have requested to create an account on our website and describing the information you provided at registration and contact information for your parent to respond and request that we stop sending you any emails, cancel your account, and/or delete, modify or edit your information. We will also use your parent’s email address to let your parent know about any changes to our Privacy Policy. Your parents may at any time review, change and/or delete any information that we have collected about you by emailing support@wevideo.com.

  * If your account is being created by a teacher, your teacher must first obtain your parent’s consent. If your teacher creates a student account for you without your parent first signing a consent form, please inform your parent immediately so that they can instruct us to remove your information from our files.

* * *

## Compliance with Privacy Shield

WeVideo complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. WeVideo has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/. In any such cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield, WeVideo understands that it may be potentially liable.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, WeVideo commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact WeVideo at support@wevideo.com. WeVideo has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland. Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel. WeVideo is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). WeVideo is required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
